<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 Raphaël Levisse</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 March 2024 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-Aware Planning</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/risk_aware_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/risk_aware_planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to assist the patient efficiently, we develop a risk-aware planning framework which finds the best manipulation plan that minimizes the fall risk probability with minimum robot effort.
We view the risk-aware planning problem from the perspective of probabilistic inference and solve it as a multi-objective optimization problem.
For the fall risk objective, we use a linear combination of expected value and CVaR to minimize the overall risk of fall while avoiding even low probabilities of high fall risks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk-Aware Decision Making in Service Robots to Minimize Risk of Patient Falls in Hospitals</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/icra-riskaware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/icra-riskaware/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Posture Optimization</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/pose_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/pose_optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although  teleoperation  is  a  promising  alternative to avoid injuries in high-risk tasks, awkward postures are still a primary contributor to works-related musculoskeletal disorders in   teleoperation.   An   ergonomically   intelligent   teleoperation system  could  reduce  risk  by  providing  feedback  for  postural correction.  In  this  project,  we  introduce  a  novel  framework for  postural  optimization  in  teleoperation  that  benefits  from common  risk  assessment  tools  in  ergonomics  and  provides online postural correction as well as optimal initial posture correction for a teleoperator according to the type of teleoperation task. We evaluate our framework in a simulated teleoperation environment  including  the  robots  and  the  human.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is The Leader Robot an Adequate Sensor for Posture Estimation and Ergonomic Assessment of A Human Teleoperator?</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/posture-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/posture-estimation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Hospital Patient Room Design</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/room_optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/room_optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite years of research into patient falls in hospital rooms, falls and related injuries remain a serious concern to patient safety. In this work, we formulate a gradient-free constrained optimization problem to generate and reconfigure the hospital room interior layout to minimize the risk of falls. We define a cost function built on a hospital room fall model that takes into account the supportive or hazardous effect of the patient’s surrounding objects, as well as simulated patient trajectories inside the room. We define a constraint set that ensures the functionality of the generated room layouts in addition to conforming to architectural guidelines. We solve this problem efficiently using a variant of simulated annealing. We present results for two real-world hospital room types and demonstrate a significant improvement of 18% on average in patient fall risk when compared with a traditional hospital room layout and 41% when compared with randomly generated layouts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Model Predictive Approach for Online Mobile Manipulation of Nonholonomic Objects using Learned Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/ijrr2019-mobile-manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/ijrr2019-mobile-manipulation/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;model_comparison.PNG&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Final displacement errors with and without feedback.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;sim_results.PNG&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;The final position and orientation errors in simulation experiments for all objects through all tasks.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;real_results.PNG&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Physical experiments results from two tasks.&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient Fall Risk Evaluation Model</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/fall_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/fall_model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A major safety concern in hospitals is patient falls. Falls often increase length of stay, reduce quality of life, and are costly to both patients and health care providers. This project focuses on fall risk prediction based on environmental features and provides an optimized patient hospital room design to decrease risk of fall. We have developed an algorithm to find fall risk distributions within a room or along a trajectory based on fixed environmental features, semi-variable patient features, and variable trajectory features. To better understand the separate influence of each feature, we are conducting a human subject study to analyze the effect of each feature on a person’s stability and risk of fall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Manipulation Planning</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/pam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/pam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project we introduce a patient assistant mobile (PAM) robot to monitor patient behavior and provide a cost-effective physical presence to continuously observe a patient and the environment to prevent falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many common objects found inside hospital rooms and personal dwellings have legs (e.g. walkers, tables, chairs, equipment stands). For a mobile robot operating in such environments, safely maneuvering these objects without collision is essential. Since providing the robot with dynamic models of all possible legged objects that may exist in such environments is not feasible, autonomous learning of an approximate dynamic model for these objects would significantly improve manipulation planning. Thus, we have developed a probabilistic algorithm that learns pre-categorized object models using minimal force and motion interactions between the robot and object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We account for multiple manipulation strategies by formulating the manipulation planning as a mixed-integer convex optimization problem. The proposed manipulation framework considers the hybrid control system comprised of i) choosing which leg to grasp, and ii) continuous applied forces to move the aid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Posture Estimation in p-HRI</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/pose_estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/project/pose_estimation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human posture estimation has been a challenging research problem and many solutions has been suggested for different applications. Mainly, marker-based motion capture system and markerless camera-bases systems are the most common methods to estimate human posture. Marker-based solutions are usually more accurate however they require a long preparation time for setting up parkers and calibration of mocap systems. Markerless are more convenient since they does not requires attaching markers on human body. Both of those methods are based on using cameras and have many limitation in real applications.
with the recent developments in physical human-robot interaction, estimating human posture is a demanding task specially in ergonomics and safety analysis, and adaption of robot motion based on human posture and motion.
In this project we propose a novel method to estimate human posture in telemanipulation. We believe that in physical interaction between human and the robot, only knowing the robot&amp;rsquo;s trajectory is adequate to estimate the human&amp;rsquo;s posture. We model the problem as a partially-observable dynamic model and use filtering and smoothing approaches to solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics Model Learning and Manipulation Planning for Objects in Hospitals Using a Patient Assistant Mobile (PAM) Robot</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/iros2018-pam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/iros2018-pam/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Planning in Danger Zones</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/course_project/rrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/course_project/rrt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, a RRT-based method to cope with quadrotor path planning problem in damaged structures is proposed. First, a Graphic User Interface (GUI) was developed to define the environment conveniently. Then, RRT was used as basic path generating method. Besides, the limit on acceleration of the robot was considered to meet its dynamic constraints, and cost function was proposed to avoid danger zones in the environment. Next, B-spline method was implemented to achieve the smoothing of the final path. Finally, obtained results of 3D visualized simulation based on ROS and OpenGL are reported which validate the performance of the proposed method.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Recognition</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/course_project/object_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/course_project/object_recognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is focused on single object recognition and classification. The MNIST database is used as the image dataset. A single layer CNN is developed which consists of a convolutional layer and a pooling layer. The results obtained for this database is test accuracy of around 97.44% which is comparable with the results found in the literature. In the next step, the single layer CNN is expanded to a three-layer CNN for the CIFAR-10 database in order to classify each image to one of the 10 known categories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Neural Gas Network Approach for Obtaining The Singularity-Free Workspace of 3-DOF Planar Parallel Manipulators</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/imeche2016-pgngn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/imeche2016-pgngn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Study on Optimal Motion Planning of Wheeled Mobile Robot Using Convex Optimization and Receding Horizon Concept</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/icrom2016-wheeled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/icrom2016-wheeled/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Motion Planning for Parallel Robots Via Convex Optimization and Receding Horizon.</title>
      <link>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/advrobotics2016-optimal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raphaellevisse.github.io/publication/advrobotics2016-optimal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
